If you've ever uploaded an app to either the Google Play Store or the iOS App Store,
如果你以前向 Google Play Store 或 iOS App Store 上传过应用
you know that what you need to do is build your app and basically bundle it to,
则知道需要构建并封装应用
if you're on Android a.apk file,
如果是 Android 应用 则要创建 apk 文件
or if you're on iOS a.ipa file.
如果是 iOS 应用 则要创建 ipa 文件
So that's what we're going to do in this video,
我们将在本视频中介绍如何创建
we're not going to actually walk through how to upload
我们不会实际地逐步介绍
an app to the App Store just because it's kind of a long process.
如何将应用上传到应用商店 因为流程很长
But what we will walk through is the toughest part of that process,
但是我们会介绍最复杂的步骤
which is building or bundling these specific files
也就是构建或封装
that you need to actually upload to the app stores.
上传到应用商店所需的具体文件
So the very first thing we're going to do is head over to your terminal,
首先 转到终端
and if you don't already have the EXP app from Expo,
如果尚无 Expo exp 应用
go ahead and install that as a global module on your computer.
则在计算机上将其安装为全局模块
I already have it so I'm not going to install it.
我已经安装了 所以不在此处进行安装
But if you don't have it, run
但是如果你没有的话
mpminstall-G.exp and then once you have that what you can do,
运行 npm install -g exp 安装之后
assuming your app is currently running and assuming you
假设你的应用目前正在运行
have updated your app.json file which we did in a previous video,
并且假设你更新了 app.json 文件 我们在上个视频中介绍过如何更新
what you can do now is if you're inside of your project,
现在如果你位于该项目中
you can run EXP, build,
则可以运行 exp build:
call an Android or call an iOS depending on what you want to build for,
android 或 ios 具体取决于你要针对的平台
I want to build for Android right now.
我暂时先为 Android 进行构建
So we run that,
运行该指令
and then it's eventually going to ask you this question.
最终 系统会问你这个问题
Would you like to upload a key store or have us generate one for you?
Would you like to upload a key store or have us generate one for you?
If you don't know what this means, let us handle it.
If you don't know what this means, let us handle it! :)
What that means is I am very gladly going to let them handle it,
我很乐意让他们为我处理这一流程
so I'm going to say one,
因此我将输入 1
let Expo handle the process.
表示让 Expo 处理这一流程
After a few minutes you're going to get a view that looks like this,
几分钟过后 你将看到这样的界面
saying hey we went ahead and started building it
表示我们开始构建了
because it's going to take forever or it's going to take a little bit while,
因为将花费无限长的时间 或一段时间
you can go ahead and monitor the build by running EXP build call status.
你可以通过运行 exp build:status 进行监控
And if we do that, you'll notice that we get some warnings, which is fine.
如果运行该指令 会出现一些警告 没关系
And it says hey your project looks good,
这里提示 Your project looks good!
checking if current build exists.
Checking if current build exists…
And then it says the build is still in progress,
然后提示依然在构建中
so wait a little bit longer.
再等等
Now, after about 15 minutes when you run the build status command,
在运行 build:status 指令大概 15 分钟后
you'll get this URL right here.
你将获得这个 URL
Now what you can do is enter in this URL into your browser,
你可以在浏览器中转到此 URL
and that will allow you to download your.apk file,
下载你的 apk 文件
and then when you are submitting your apps to the app store,
当你将应用提交到应用商店时
when they ask you for your.apk file,
系统会提示你提供 apk 文件
you can just give them this file right here that you downloaded from this URL.
你可以直接提供从此 URL 上下载的文件
Now if you want to do that exact same process but for iOS,
现在 对于 iOS 流程来说 基本差不多
all you need to do is run EXP build:iOS.,
只需运行 exp build:iOS
and that will give you a.ipa file to upload when the iOS App Store asks you for that.
这样就会获得一个 ipa 文件并在上传到 iOS App Store 时提供该文件